Godson Obielum

No 33 Putney Road, Leicester, UK +44 7563578780

godsonobielum47@gmail.com

https://linkedin.com/in/obielum-godson

https://devgson.github.io/

OBJECTIVE STATEMENT

Individual with about 2 years of experience in software development across the stack, currently studying for an Msc in Advanced Computer Science. Seeking to learn and advance my growing tech career by undergoing a Summer internship which will provide an opportunity where i may be able to use my skills to solve complex problems by designing and developing scalable and state-of-the-art software applications.

EDUCATION

Advanced Computer Science, University Of Leicester

January 2020 - Present

- » Certificate to be obtained: Master of Science
- » Current Modules: Analysis and Design of Algorithms, Cryptography and Info. Security, Semantic Web
- » Expected Grade: Distinction

Computer Science (Technology), Babcock University

August 2013 - June 2017

- » Certificate Obtained: Bachelor of Science
- » Grade: Second Class Upper (4.13)
- » Modules Completed: Database design and management, Java, C++, Data Structures and algorithm, etc.
- » Final Year Project: Smart Plant Irrigation and Treatment System

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Fullstack Developer - BetaQuick, Maryland, USA

July 2019 - November 2019

- » Worked remotely together with a team of 5 on a Healthcare management system.
- » Implemented features such as secure two-way communication between doctors and patients, booking appointments, submitting diagnostic forms, creating detailed prescriptions for each assigned patient.
- » Implemented seperate docker containers across the stack and made each container communicate with each other over a network.
- » Made onboarding for new developers seamless by designing a technical documentation and onboarding specifications.
- » Achieved a 99% test code-coverage on the projects codebase and also implemented E2E tests.

Backend Developer - Softcom, Lagos, Nigeria

December 2018 - June 2019

- » Worked with a team of 7 that built an application for monitoring the quarterly performance of all employees in the company using KPI's such as weekly tasks, monthly objectives set by each manager.
- » Architectured the backend system of an application that was used to collect individual and company appraisals for each quarter from employees, managers and key stakeholders in the company.
- » Designed the central database for storing all employee details.
- » Created an internal hub for employees in the company which made the company structure more transparent, eased communication between employees and made company-wide requests seamless.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Guest Technical Author - AuthO, USA

June 2018 - Present

- » Published technical articles that help developers seamlessly implement authentication and authorization in their applications using Auth0.
- » Worked on technical articles that aim to simplify certain complex Javascript concepts and tools.
- » Delivered blog posts that teach on how to implement features using certain tools and frameworks.
- » Published articles that are read by an audience of up to 250,000 developers worldwide.

Freelance Software Developer

February 2016 - June 2018

- » Contributed to the community through various open source projects.
- » Designed RESTful API's with Node and Express, and storage of data with databases such as mongoDB.
- » Used version control when working on client projects to enable a more controlled and fluid worklow.
- » Setup pipelines for CI/CD after deploying projects through BaaS providers.
- » Built applications dependent on third party API's provided by various platforms.

SOFT SKILLS

- » A proven ability of developing solutions to technical problems using examples such as when i had to create a complex leave request system for the employees at Softcom.
- » Well honed public speaking skills acquired through publicly presenting projects and software demos to clients and stakeholders during my time working at Softcom and BetaQuick.
- » Able to utilize collaborative environments by brainstorming with team members, consulting with experienced colleagues, all with the aim of developing the right solution to a problem.
- » Adequate time management skills learnt through delivering projects within strict deadlines especially during my time as Softcom.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

- » Most Innovative Final Year Projects (2017) Second Place
- » Top chess player in Computer Science department (2016)
- » Implemented the NUBAN scheme algorithm in Javascript.
- » Chosen to be a Mentor at Andela's "ALC with Google" program.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

» Html5 » Node.js » Docker
» CSS » Java » SQL

» Bootstrap » Express » MongoDB

» Javascript » Angular » AJAX

» Jquery » Typescript

CERTIFICATIONS

- » POISE PSENSE Training
- » A+ Hardware
- » EC Council Certified Secure Computer User (CSCU)
- » Graduate Member Computer Professionals of Nigeria
- » Udacity Mobile Web Specialist

SOFTWARE SIDE-PROJECTS

Nodachat

A chat application built using Node.js

Budgetify

An ongoing personal project which allows users keep track of income and expenses.

Listing Hub

A web app that allows users find top restaurants within their area.

PUBLICATIONS

- » <u>Developing Real Time Apps with Firebase</u>
- » Developing a Real Time Editor with Pusher
- » API Authentication with JWT's and Passport
- » Implementing Role-based Access control in Node
- » Building a Telegram Bot with Node.js
- » Understanding Iterators and Iterables in Javascript
- » Building a TCP Chat Server with Node
- » <u>Using the Instagram API with Node and Express</u>